ryanwaggoner.com 2019-05-03

# Privacy Policy - Ryan Waggoner

## This privacy policy was adapted from the Automattic (makers of WordPress.com) privacy policy, which they have generously licensed under Creative Commons.

If you have questions about anything related to privacy [contact me](https://ryanwaggoner.com/contact/).

I, Ryan Waggoner, operate this website, RyanWaggoner.com. It is my policy to respect your privacy regarding any information may collected while operating this website or any related sites.

### Website Visitors

Like most websites, RyanWaggoner.com collects non-personally-identifying information of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. The purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how visitors use this website. From time to time, I may release non-personally-identifying information in the aggregate, e.g., by publishing a report on trends in the usage of its website.

RyanWaggoner.com also collects potentially personally-identifying information like Internet Protocol (IP) addresses for logged in users and for users leaving comments on blog posts. RyanWaggoner.com only discloses logged in user and commenter IP addresses under the same circumstances that it uses and discloses personally-identifying information as described below, except that blog commenter IP addresses are visible and disclosed to the administrators of the blog where the comment was left.

### Gathering of Personally-Identifying Information

Certain visitors to this website choose to interact with me in ways that require me to gather personally-identifying information. The amount and type of information that I gather depends on the nature of the interaction. For example, I may ask visitors who contact me for their name, email address, and other identifying information. Those who engage in transactions with me – by engaging me for consulting services, for example – are asked to provide additional information, including as necessary the personal and financial information required to process those transactions. In each case, I collect such information only insofar as is necessary or appropriate to fulfill the purpose of the visitor’s interaction with me. I do not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below. And visitors can always refuse to supply personally-identifying information, with the caveat that it may prevent them from engaging in certain website-related activities.

### Aggregated Statistics

I may collect statistics about the behavior of visitors to this website and I may display this information publicly or provide it to others. However, I do not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below.

### Protection of Certain Personally-Identifying Information

I disclose potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only to those of my employees, contractors and affiliated organizations that (i) need to know that information in order to process it on my behalf or to provide services available at RyanWaggoner.com or related websites, and (ii) that have agreed not to disclose it to others. Some of those employees, contractors and affiliated organizations may be located outside of your home country; by using RyanWaggoner.com and related websites, you consent to the transfer of such information to them. I will not rent or sell potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information to anyone. Other than to its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations, as described above, I disclose potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only when required to do so by law, or when I believe in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of myself, third parties or the public at large. If you send me a request, I reserve the right to publish it in order to help clarify or respond to your request or to help support other users. I take all measures reasonably necessary to protect against the unauthorized access, use, alteration or destruction of potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information.

### Cookies

A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’s computer, and that the visitor’s browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. RyanWaggoner.com uses cookies to help identify and track visitors, their usage of this website, and their website access preferences. RyanWaggoner.com visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using RyanWaggoner.com and related websites, with the drawback that certain features of these websites may not function properly without the aid of cookies.

### Ads

Ads appearing on any of my websites may be delivered to users by advertising partners, who may set cookies. These cookies allow the ad server to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement to compile information about you or others who use your computer. This information allows ad networks to, among other things, deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you. This Privacy Policy covers the use of cookies by RyanWaggoner.com and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers.

### Privacy Policy Changes

Although most changes are likely to be minor, I may change this Privacy Policy from time to time, and in my sole discretion. I encourage visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to the Privacy Policy. Your continued use of this site after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change.
